## Hamza Sohaib

### Electrical Engineer, Certified Web developer

☐ 1 (226)-506-3565

https://github.com/aka47coder

• 86 Oakville Ave, London, ON, N5V 2S6

Permanent Resident in Canada | Willing to Relocate

#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Technical-minded, detail-oriented, and a Bachelor of Electrical Engineering graduate. A capable leader having led multiple academic projects to completion in a team environment. A full stack developer with strong coding, analytical, and problem-solving skills. I relish the opportunity to use my creativity and intuition to develop meaningful software. I have proven experience working collaboratively with both colleagues and customers, and I am diligent in my pursuit of a solution for any problem I am tasked with. I pride myself on my relentless work ethic, my team-first attitude, and my drive to grow as a developer every day

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: C/C++,C#,Python,Css,HTML,jQuery,AJAX
- Frameworks & Libraries: Node.js, React, Angular, Rails, jQuery, Express, EJS, Flask, Nest.js, SCSS, WebSockets, Socket.IO, Bootstrap, Material-UI, styled-components
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Version Control: Git
- Testing: Mocha, Chai ,Jest, Cypress, Rspec, Storybook, React Testing Library
- Web/Application Servers: Tomcat, HTTP Server, Apache
- Virtual Machines: AWS, VMware, Microsoft and Google Cloud, Vagrant

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Electrical Engineering (B.Eng)

Jan 2017 - Aug 2020

University of Windsor, ON, Canada

#### **PROJECTS**

Quiz App Nov 2021

- An app that lets you create guizzes and share them between friends.
- The creator of the quiz can view and share all the results at the end of the quiz.

Front End: ¡Query, ¡Query UI, Bootstrap, SCSS.

Back End: Node, Express, PostgreSQL, Ajax.

Interview Scheduler Jan 2022

A scheduler that can create, edit and delete interview appointments.

Front-end: React, HTML, SCSS. Back-end: Node, Express, SQL.

Tweeter Dec 2021

A single page dynamic Twitter clone.

Front End: jQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS

Back End: Node, Express, EJS

TinyApp Nov 2021

A full stack web app built with Node and Express that allows users to shorten long URLs

Back End: Node, Express, EJS

Front End: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Lighthouse Labs Nov 2021

WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Electromac Group (Canada)**

August 2021 - September 2021

#### **Quality inspection**

- Responsible for the final stages of product manufactured before shipping to customers
- Support the maintenance, tooling, quality, and logistics departments
- Utilize lean-manufacturing principles and participate in action workouts to improve process capability, reduce overall costs, and increase outflow
- Abide by all Company policies including, but not limited to the following: Health and Safety, Environmental, Quality, Human Resources policies, and the Employee Handbook
- Perform quality checks and ensure product meets specifications

#### Internship (Technical Support for Desktops and Laptops)

#### **Premier Systems Pvt. Ltd**

June 2015 - June 2016

- Responded to inquires of clients remotely, in person, via chat, via telephone and email
- Adhere to milestone dates, status, and coordination between different stakeholders
- Scheduled appointments and maintained appointment calendars
- Coordinate and/or perform remote fixes at the desktop level, including installing and upgrading software, implementing file backups, and configuring systems and applications
- Troubleshoot hardware & accurately determine fixes
- Maintain, troubleshoot, and control local area network (LAN) use, broadband (WAN) network use

#### Internship

Serena Hotel June 2013 - July 2013

- Gained knowledge about different departments of the hotel to troubleshooting of various hotel application software
- Trained hotel staff in using of MS-Word, Excel, and dedicated applications software
- Installed PCs, Printers, Cash registers and scanners in various departments of hotel
- Network Administration of IT equipment used in hotel including Wi-Fi repeaters